<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="48"><page Index="1" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Bellefaire JCBfor excellence... for wellness... for childreAnnual Report 2013-2014n]]></page><page Index="2" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ii ]]></page><page Index="3" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[1Bellefaire JCB MissionBellefaire JCB is an innovative organization that provides exceptional care, education, and advocacy to enhance the emotional, physical and intellectual well-being of children, young adults, and families in the Jewish and general communities.In addition to providing direct services, Bellefaire JCB is committed to:•	Remaining on the forefront of the youth services and child caring fields•	Responding to emerging needs •	Building knowledge which contributesto service to children, youth and their families•	Advocating on behalf of children, youth and their familiesBellefaire JCB provides its services without regard to race, religion, sex or national origin, and encourages all clients to develop positive identifi- cation with their religious and ethnic backgrounds.The Bellefaire mission becomes real in the lives of so many children, youth and their families thanks to the values we adhere to every day; values which are basic to the work of all our staff members and associates.Each day we strive to:•	Protect and nurture children and youth•	Respect and value the family •	Provide a safe, nurturingenvironment•	Maximize each individual’s potential•	Respect personal worth and individuality•	Consider the whole person•	Acknowledge and respect the cultural and ethnic diversity of everyone associated with Bellefaire]]></page><page Index="4" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Dear FriendsJust as a child develops and her personality evolves, so has Bellefaire JCB with the passing of each year. Our services keep expanding — the programming grows. The 2014 fiscal year at Bellefaire JCB has been one of evolution as well. Addressing the diverse needs of our clients and students has kept us on our toes.Throughout the year, Bellefaire JCB provided services for 22,000 children, youth and families – a 55% increase in just five years. More than 3,200 Jewish clients and their families accessed our services through programs including Jewish Day School Counseling, Jewish Big Brother Big Sister, and Jewish Day Nursery (JDN) Early Childhood Center. And our in-home and community-based programs assisted nearly 14,000 children, youth, and their families.Although we have received national attention for our treatment and prevention services for youth with behavioral and mental health issues, our early childhood education programs also deserve a standing ovation. Bellefaire JCB’s award- winning JDN Early Childhood Center and Monarch Center for Autism Preschool provided structured lessons and targeted interventions that allowe even the most challenged of our littlest butterflies to soar.At JDN parents and staff were uplifted by the experiential learning and social milestones the youngsters accomplished on a daily basis — providing an important springboard to each child’s future.At Bellefaire JCB Monarch Center for Autism, our staff’s intensive early intervention approaches changed the lives of children on the autism spectrum. The fact that several of the children who enrolled in this program at age 3 attended kindergarten at their neighborhood school by age 6, attests to the program’s effectiveness. Our staff frequently receives notes from current and former school parents like the one to the right.“Today was Moms-n-Muffins day at school and I spent the morning with Sarah in her classroom and then volun- teered in the art room.Today I realized that our short- term goal of wanting her to function as independently as possible in kindergarten has really happened. She is doing great, making friends, needing minimal assistance withdaily assignments, and really understanding and enjoying the daily routine.Things cannot be going better and I have all of you to thank for helping us get to this point.”2]]></page><page Index="5" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[The impact that Bellefaire makes in the schools, your homes, and our community continues to expand. Whether empowering teens to be upstanders, helping families through the adoption process, or counseling youth with mental health, behavorial or substance abuse issues, Bellefaire has been there. This annual report highlights many of these accomplishments.We scored brilliantly during Take A Closer Look, our Homeless Youth Awareness Campaign, which focused on the plight of homeless youth. We received extensive local, national, and international media coverage for this dramatic and evocative campaign (read more on page 4).Addressing the needs of the growing adult population with autism prompted us to open a supported living home nearby Bellefaire’s campus for four adults with autism. And nearly 40 individuals participated in our Adult Autism Day Vocational Habilitation Program — up from six participants two years ago.And there was much to celebrate as we partnered with Oswald Companies to dedicate the Foster Care and Adoption wing in honor of Marc S. Byrnes, a highly recognized industry and civic leader with a deep-rooted history with Bellefaire JCB.It has been a busy year, one that would not have been as successful without the support of our staff, lay leadership, and private and public funders. As we look ahead, we will not waiver from caring for children, young adults, and families by providing appropriate services for their emotional, physical, and intellectual well being. And like the butterfly, all we need is to have the wind at our back.In MemoriamIn December 2014 Bellefaire JCB experienced the tragic loss of dear friend and beloved board member Marc Krantz. We wish to take this opportunity to express deepest sympathy to his family, friends, and colleagues.Bradley J. SchlangChair, Board of DirectorsAdam G. Jacobs, Ph.D.President3]]></page><page Index="6" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Take A Closer Look at Youth Homelessness — Cleveland Campaign Raises AwarenessMay 2014. A dramatic and evocative campaign focused on the plight of homeless youth hits the streets of Cleveland. Centering the campaign is the placement of dozens of lifelike and provocative faceless figures — “Somebodies” — each with a sweatshirt and floor sticker citing issues homeless youth face such as fears of domestic violence, LGBT status, or human trafficking.CAMPAIGN GOALS•	Raise awareness of the homeless youth epidemic in Cuyahoga County (Cleveland, OH).•	Create empathy for and under- standing of homeless youth who are often misunderstood.•	Increase awareness of the services available through Bellefaire JCB’s Homeless and Missing Youth Program.MULTIFACETED APPROACH•	30- and 60-second Public Service Announcements (PSAs).•	Social media saturation uses hashtag #saveclekids.•	Posters and banners feature campaign messaging and additional calls to action.•	Multimedia coverage in print, radio, and television.IMPACT EXCEEDS EXPECTATIONS•	23,000 views of PSA on YouTube worldwide.•	Social media posts reach over 670,000 users.•	Global TV and print coverage includes local networks and ABC affiliates nationally, The Plain Dealer, Huffington Post, Yahoo!Finance UK, USA Today, Grazia, Latin Trends and Ads of the World.Learn more at saveCLEkids.org4]]></page><page Index="7" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[5]]></page><page Index="8" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Program Overview – JDN Early Childhood CenterWhen JDN Early Childhood Center opened in 1922 as Jewish Day Nursery, no one could have imagined that 93 years later the center would develop into an early childhood program that goes far beyond a typical childcare center. To better reflect the enhanced programming and diverse student base, the name changed to JDN Early Childhood Center after joining with Bellefaire JCB in 1945. We take pride in knowing that our program helps children develop self-awareness, respect, and acceptance of other people and cultures.Each year we enhance and expand our quality full-day, year-round programming for children 6 weeks to 5 years old. These efforts were rewarded in the fall of 2014 when JDN became the first Jewish early childhood program to earn Ohio’s Step Up To Quality’s 5-star rating.The focus at JDN is to foster academic readiness, confidence, self-control, creativity, and a love of learning. Our team of degreed educators and staff attend to the social, emotional, cognitive, and physical needs of the children, and are supported by the child behavior and mental health experts at Bellefaire JCB. Our goals are to promote intellectual curiosity, foster a love of learning, and create an atmosphere in which children feel that their teachers respect and validate their interests.Although JDN is a Jewish school, it is not a religious school. We teach about Jewish holidays, traditions, and values. Discussions deal with justice, forgiveness, caring, freedom, love, and sharing — important basics of Jewish program- ming at the early childhood level.Both Jewish and national holidays are celebrated, and the children celebrate the Jewish Sabbath each Friday by reciting the Hebrew blessings, lighting the candles, and enjoying grape juice and Challah.Our Jewish programming is enhanced with enrichment classes including music, art, and natural science.Literacy, science concepts, art, fundamental math, music, and physical development are all interwoven throughout the curriculum.Each teacher takes an active role in the care and education of every child at JDN — from the intentional and purposeful lesson plans, to the individual child assessments and screening of developmental milestones and academic checkpoints. The children gain critical kindergarten readiness skills through social play, computers, and a variety of other activities in an atmosphere where each individual child is challenged and relationships are the focus. The ultimate goal at JDN is for children to feel joy in learning and pride in their efforts and accomplishments.6]]></page><page Index="9" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[7]]></page><page Index="10" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[8Unlocking the Puzzle]]></page><page Index="11" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[From the moment 4-year-old Madeline walked into Ruth’s preschool classroom at JDN there was no doubt where the action was going to be that year.]]></page><page Index="12" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[“Our goal was not to crush Madeline’s spirit but to change her “I knew Madeline was going to give us a run for our money, but I also knew that this delightfully energetic and creative child would quickly find a place in all our hearts.” said Ruth.Much of Madeline’s behavior stemmed from the fact that her parents had demanding professional lives that prevented them from spending time with their only child; they were also overwhelmed by Madeline’s strong personality. Madeline had learned that if she screamed long and loud enough she could manipulate her parents into giving her attention or anything else she wanted.In class, when Madeline was told she could not have all the toy ponies for herself, or that a new friend wanted to play with someone else, she threw herself down on the floor and had a howling tantrum — upsetting everyone around her.To calm her down Ruth hugged Madeline and told her “I know you are mad and sad, but Ben is playing with Sophie instead of you this morning so you have to choose another friend to play with.” When this approach didn’t work, Ruth suggested that Madeline spend time with Paula Friedman, JDN assistant director.Paula’s small office, tucked away off JDN’s main hallway, became one of Madeline’s favorite plac- es. The room has pictures of flowers on the wall, a water fountain, stuffed animals, small squishy balls, cozy wraps, soothing music, and low lights. As Madeline relaxed in Paula’s office the two talked about feelings, did stretching exercises, and practiced taking deep breaths. After about15 minutes Madeline would be ready to return to the classroom where she usually meandered over to the arts and crafts table.10]]></page><page Index="13" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[negative behavior so she could feel better inside.”Using paper, glue, and crayons, Madeline worked on projects of her own design that showed great imagination and style. Ruth seized on this opportunity for the two of them to use brightly colored sticky notes to write books about feelings. Madeline also had a flair for fashion and created outrageously whimsical but highly ingenious ensembles at the dress-up corner.“We soon realized that art was the key to unlocking the puzzle that had been Madeline,” said Ruth. “She channeled her high energy and emotions into whatever creative project she was work- ing on. Our goal was not to crush Madeline’s spirit but to change her negative behavior so she could feel better inside.”With Paula’s professional help and Ruth’s patient guidance, Madeline began to feel much more comfortable in class. She learned how to share toys and friends, and to control her tantrums. It also helped that mid-year Madeline’s mother reduced her working hours. To their mutual delight, mother and daughter began spending quality time together each day.Madeline soon realized her potential and became a delightful preschooler. The last day of the school year Madeline’s mother presented Ruth with a stack of books and a large pad of sticky notes with the enclosed card: “Many thanks to a teacher who realized that sticky notes can be turned into future pieces of art.”11]]></page><page Index="14" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[The Year at Bellefaire JCB: 2013–2014JULY 2013Four-bed Crisis Stabilization and Assessment unit opens, providing 24-hour critical care and observation in a secure, structured setting for youth who require treatment.AUGUST 2013Over 460 participants and 100 volunteers support the 18th Annual Biathlon and Walk.Monarch School students present Art Interprets Autism art exhibit in collaboration with Artists Archives ofthe Western Reserve and University Hospitals of Cleveland.SEPTEMBER 2013Over 200 guests attend the dedication of the Foster Care and Adoption wing to Marc S. Byrnes, chairman of Oswald Companies and highly recognized civic leader with a longstanding history with Bellefaire JCB. This generous donation was made on behalf of Oswald owner-employees who also built a playground on campus.NOVEMBER 2013Jewish Big Brother Big Sister Program hosts the 24th annual Bowl for Kids’ Sake and attracts nearly 300 children and adults; raising funds that support mentoring programming.12]]></page><page Index="15" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[DECEMBER 2013Annual Holiday Gift Giving Program generates gifts from the community for nearly 1,500 youth served by the agency.JANUARY 2014Bellefaire’s Homeless and Missing Youth program partners with statewide initiative to raise awareness of human trafficking.MAY 2014Dozens of “Somebodies,” lifelike and provocative faceless figures, hit the streets as part of the Take A Closer Look campaign to raise awareness of youth homelessness.JUNE 2014Bellefaire opens a supported living home near campus for four adults with autism.Monarch School graduates 11 students who all meet transition goals successfully and pursue either employ- ment, continuing education, or transition/vocational training.13]]></page><page Index="16" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[14The Right Preschool]]></page><page Index="17" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[When 3-year-old Parker entered JDN a year ago he suddenly had lots of new things in his life — new friends, new school and a new language.]]></page><page Index="18" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[“Parker turned into a sunny happy preschooler who happilyParker, whose parents are from Beijing, spoke fluent Mandarin and only a smattering of English.The east-meets-west language barrier posed a challenge that JDN staff had successfully handled before, but there was one other matter that needed attention. During the critical new student transition week, Parker’s mother, who had started a new job, sent her Mandarin speaking mother- in-law with Parker.At JDN the parent-child transition to ease children into their classroom life is thoughtfully planned. “Our goal is for parents or caregivers to stay for steadily decreasing periods during a child’s first week at which point the children are usually comfortable enough to be left with their teachers and classmates,” said Suzanne Appel, JDN director.But Parker was so reliant on his grandmother — and vise versa — that every time the elderly woman tried to leave the room or the nearby hallway, the 3-year-old let out piercing shrieks that rang throughout the building.Parker’s “big feelings” affected his classmates and the teaching staff. It was also an unwelcomed distraction as his grandmother constantly entered the classroom to wipe Parker’s tears, help him in the bathroom, clean his face after lunch, pat his back during rest periods and bundle him up in layers of clothes for outdoor play.After three weeks the teacher and the rest of the JDN staff knew this could not go on.16]]></page><page Index="19" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[waved bye-bye to his mom at drop-off each morning,”Upon conferring with the JDN support team it was determined that “grandma had to go,” said Suzanne. “We realized Parker’s separation anxiety and ability to integrate into the classroom and learn English was not being helped by having grandma with him.”After a discussion with Parker’s mother, it was agreed upon that it would be best if grandma stayed home.To help ease Parker’s anxiety, a storyboard to show him pictures of classroom activities was used. The teacher pointed to pictures of children saying good-bye to their moms, kids at play, and children eating snacks. When Parker had an occasional meltdown, some of his older classmates came to his side and held his hand or patted his back.Within a few weeks Parker began to enjoy preschool, successfully bonded with his teacher and interacted with the other children. He added new English words to his vocabulary every day.“He turned into a sunny preschooler who happily waved bye-bye to his mom at drop-off each morning,” said Suzanne.Parker’s parents are grateful their son has achieved so much at JDN. “He absolutely loves coming to JDN each morning,” said his mother. “He sings lots of songs, knows many numbers and letters, and can even read and write simple words. All of these amazing changes have happened because of JDN teachers and staff. There is no doubt we found the right preschool for our son.”17]]></page><page Index="20" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[18]]></page><page Index="21" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[19Community ImpactIn 2013–2014 Bellefaire JCB served nearly 22,000 youth and families.]]></page><page Index="22" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Community ImpactBELLEFAIRE JCB••• •Bellefaire is awarded Governor’s Hotspot funding to provide a crisis bed for clients with both Mental Health and Autism Spectrum diagnoses in partnership with the ADAMHS Board of Cuyahoga County and Board of Developmental Disabilities. This program is a first-of-its kind model for the community.Social Advocates for Youth (SAY) staff serve on the Cuyahoga County Opiate Task Force Partnership for Prevention, a statewide initiative sponsored by the Ohio Department of Health to address the epidemic rise in unintentional fatalities associated with the misuse of prescription medication, advocating for the passage of Ohio legislation concerning opiate overdoses including the Good Samaritan Law, Project DAWN, and other issues related to the misuse of opiates and heroin.The agency starts a legal extern program in an affiliation with Case Western Reserve University School of Law.The agency receives a state-funded Behavioral Health-Juvenile Justice grant in partnership with Lorain County Mental Health Board to provide an integrated co-occurring treatment team to support adolescents with both mental health and substance abuse diagnoses.20]]></page><page Index="23" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[•• ••• •Drs. First, the electronic prescribing module connected to the Electronic Health Record, is launched and allows client prescriptions to be sent to pharmacies electronically.Bellefaire becomes a Pennsylvania Medicaid provider.The school-based program is the recipient of a grant from the ADAMHS Board of Cuyahoga County to cover services for youth with lapsed Medicaid coverage and who have no other funding to support prevention and/or counseling services.The agency continues its clinical consultation relationship with the Education Corps of the Israel Defense Forces at Havat Hashomer Army Base in Israel. The focus of the collaboration involves providing guidance and consultation on development and implementation of home-, community- and school-based counseling programs for at-risk youth.Bellefaire recieves its Alcohol and Other Drug (AOD) Medicaid Certification.Based on Ohio Scales, a widely used evaluation tool, 89% of clients and 94% of their parents/guardians are satisfied with the mental health services they received from Bellefaire JCB.21]]></page><page Index="24" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Community ImpactMONARCH CENTER FOR AUTISMDay School and Preschool Transition Education ProgramResidential Therapeutic Treatment – Boarding AcademyMonarch Hall Residence for AdultsLifeworks – Adult Autism Day Habilitation ProgramSummer Social Language ProgramFamily Training, Support and Social Activities•• •Monarch School enrollment is over 115 students. It receives an impressive rating; 97% of parents rate services as “Excellent” or “Good,” and 100% agree that their child benefitted from his/her experience at Monarch.The Adult Autism day vocational habilitation program experiences significant growth with nearly 40 individuals participating — up from six two years ago.Monarch School develops and pilots PACE (Preposition Action Concept Evaluation), an assessment that evaluates how students most effectively understand spoken directives that contain a preposition (verbal directions, static scene cues, or dynamic cues). Preliminary findings demonstrate that students under- stand significantly more when given a static visual support or a video model.22]]></page><page Index="25" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[••Monarch’s technology advancements include the integration of more than 100 iPads and 19 SmartBoards at the school, and over 300 new educational resources in the Media Center. More than 3,400 total educational resources are now used by students and staff at Monarch.The agency undertakes an initiative to establish a best-practice model proving ground for the long-term vision of creating intentional, guided, and self-sustaining community-based living situations for adults with Autism Spectrum Disorder. As a first step of meeting this goal, a residential property is purchased near the Shaker Campus where four young adults live with Monarch staff.23]]></page><page Index="26" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Community Impact24RESIDENTIAL SERVICESCrisis Stabilization and AssessmentsIntensive TreatmentTransitional and Independent LivingCo-occurring Mental Health/ Substance Abuse TreatmentAutism Residential Therapeutic Treatment – Monarch Boarding AcademyFOSTER CARE AND ADOPTIONInfant AdoptionHague Accreditation for International AdoptionsWaiting Child Adoption Treatment Foster Care••• •A four-bed Crisis Stabilization and Assessment unit opens and provides 24-hour critical care and observation in a locked, structured setting for youth requiring short- term treatment.Monarch Boarding Academy welcomes autism residential clients from California, Illinois, Kentucky, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, West Virginia, and Wisconsin.A member of the agency’s Adoption team is awarded Triad Advocate of the Year from Adoption Network of Cleveland for “outstanding advocacy and edu- cation efforts on behalf of birthparents as they navigate the adoption process.”The Foster Care team engages Ideas in Focus to gain insight into what brings individuals to the calling of being a foster parent and what retains them.]]></page><page Index="27" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[25VOLUNTEER PROGRAMJewish Big Brother Big SisterWatch the video here: vimeo.com/90229802PRESCHOOL, CHILDCARE, AND EDUCATIONJDN Early Childhood Center Monarch Preschool for Autism• •Recruiting efforts to young professionals ramp up through the development of a pro bono video produced by Drive to Create, and the formation of a Strategic Growth Initiative Committee.Annual Bowl for Kids’ Sake attracts more than 300 participants and raises critical funds that support matches.•	Early childhood education services continue strong with approximately 80 children enrolled in the infant, toddler, and preschool programs at JDN and eight students at Monarch Preschool.•	JDN’s curriculum is enhanced through an increased emphasis on intentional and purposeful lesson plans, the development of more detailed child assessment and screening of developmental milestones and academic checkpoints, and an increased staff profes- sional development training program.]]></page><page Index="28" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Community ImpactCOUNSELING AND COMMUNITY SERVICESOutpatient Child and Family CounselingPsychiatry/Pharmacologic ManagementPsychological Testing and Evaluation In-Home Family Preservation Services Substance Abuse TreatmentSocial Advocates for Youth (SAY) Prevention and Early Intervention ProgramSchool-based Counseling After School Group CounselingHomeless and Missing Youth Services•• ••School-based counselors and social workers support over 1,600 children in 73 school districts throughout the region who are referred by teachers and administrators due to behavior problems or mental/behavioral health issues.The outpatient counseling program develops a fire-starter assessment to determine if there is a level of risk, and provides referrals to coordinate care.Social Advocates for Youth (SAY) provides prevention, early identification, referral and education services to over 8,200 teens and their families at no cost to the families or schools.Our impact in Lorain County significantly expands by serving over 1,000 children and their families with psychiatry, outpatient therapy, intensive home-based treatment and/or wraparound services, school-based services, co-occurring mental health and substance abuse treatment, and psychological testing.26]]></page><page Index="29" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[• •• •Jewish Day School counselors provide direct behavioral health care services and consultation to 950 students and their parents individually, in classrooms and in small groups.The agency launches Healthy Moms, Happy Families program in a partner- ship with the Cleveland Regional Perinatal Depression Network. It promotes the physical and mental health of pregnant women and new mothers and their babies.A telepsychiatry Outpatient Psychiatry Clinic is launched with weekend hours, increasing capacity and client/family access to Outpatient Psychiatry.The Lorain office staff is involved in the highly regarded Suicide Prevention Workgroup that provides essential consultation and suicide prevention services throughout Lorain county.27]]></page><page Index="30" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Program Overview – Monarch PreschoolMonarch Center for Autism opened its doors in 2000 to the first students of Monarch School, a chartered non-public day school for students with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD). As the curric- ulum and programming expanded over the years, so did the obvious need for an early childhood program. In 2006, Monarch Preschool opened as an intensive, therapeutic early childhood program for children ages 3 to 6 with suspected or confirmed ASD diagnosis.Monarch Preschool is located in Monarch School on Bellefaire JCB’s 32-acre campus. The facility was designed to create a supportive learning environment for students with ASD. The school uses the Monarch Model, which was developed in collaboration with Harvard Medical School and Boston Children’s Hospital’s Autism Language Program. This highly effective model, which combines concept-driven language instruction, visual supports, and technology, complements the treatment method that’s most appropriate for each child.Class is held five days a week, 11 months a year, with options for students to attend either full day or half-day. The curriculum is aligned with the Ohio Department of Education’s Early Learning and Development Standards, and is a provider for the State of Ohio Autism Scholarship Program.The program at Monarch Preschool has been designed to meet the needs of all children on the spectrum — from high functioning to highly impaired. Each student receives individual instruction in a supportive environment that fosters meaningful communication and primary school readiness. Teams include a supervisor; intervention specialist; speech, occupational and recreation therapists; behavior specialist; music and art therapists; and associate teachers. This integrated approach eliminates the need to go to multiple therapists, which could be disruptive to a child’s daily routine.The Monarch team focuses on social and play skill development, language- based communication, executive functioning pre-academic skills, activities of daily living; fine and gross motor and self-help skills; sensory intervention; and behavioral support. Families receive daily communication, attend bimonthly meetings with teachers and therapists, and may opt to receive quarterly home visits. Additionally, family networking and training sessions are available.The ultimate goals for Monarch Preschool students are to provide intervention and kindergarten readiness — whether the path is in the child’s home school district or continuing at Monarch School.28]]></page><page Index="31" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[29]]></page><page Index="32" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Stea y Progress30p]]></page><page Index="33" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[On a cool, sunny April morning Benjamin walked through the Monarch Center for Autism Preschool lobby with a fistful of flowers, greeting his teacher with “Look Ms. Erin, this flower smells good.” Holding his teacher’s hand,the two headed to the classroom where Benjamin asked for help removing his jacket and stashing his lunch of noodles, yogurt, and fruit in his cubby.]]></page><page Index="34" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[“...we tailor every moment in our small classes to every child’s Benjamin is in a group of eight children ages 3 to 6 who are on the Autism Spectrum and spend their days in a program that creates a supportive learning environment. Each classroom at the school is designed to meet the unique sensory, communication, behavior, and academic needs of individuals with ASD.“If someone had told me a year ago that Benjamin would be able to speak in short sentences, engage in cooperative play, and ask for help, I would never have believed it, “ said Marissa, Benjamin’s mother. “In my mind Monarch staff are royalty and should be wearing jeweled crowns on their heads.” Marissa credits Monarch’s intensive early intervention practices as a key component to Benjamin’s success.Marissa’s gratitude is well founded. When Benjamin started Monarch Preschool at age 3, he had limited balance and mobility — scooting to get around — and no coordinated control. He had low muscle tone, was not toilet trained, and his diet was limited to four pureed foods.After a careful assessment of Benjamin’s strengths and weaknesses, the Monarch Preschool team developed an intensive individualized education plan (IEP) with quantitative, measurable goals. “We tailor every moment in our small classes to each child’s unique learning requirements,” said Debra Mandell, director of Monarch School.All IEP goals are worked on across all settings by the entire team — an intervention specialist, associate teachers, speech-language pathologist, occupational and recreational therapists, music and art therapists, and a behavioral specialist.“The Monarch Model is a visual language immersion process and incorporates dynamic language us- ing iPads, computers, and static cards with still images,” explains Mrs. Mandell. “Visual processing has proven to be very successful at Monarch.”32]]></page><page Index="35" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[unique learning requirements,”Students have a daily schedule that looks similar to a typical preschool setting. In addition to art, music, and story/circle time, each student works on gross motor skills with a recreational therapist and has two to four individual therapeutic sessions per day. Their steady progress, though incremental, brings daily gratification to teachers and specialists. Not to mention unparalleled joy and hope to their families. In many cases, staff are on their knees modeling behavior, imitating tasks, and reteaching often.When Benjamin came to Monarch Preschool, he could use a dozen single words such as “bye-bye” and “mama.” He would not imitate a modeled word, had no response skills, inconsistently responded to his name, and had fleeting eye contact. The approach involved maintaining consistency in his schedule and the people around him, daily repetition, and engaging Benjamin in activities that used new words. To initiate joint attention, Benjamin was taught to first have eye contact, then to point.In order to expand the food Benjamin ate, a systematic approach was implemented that included increasing sensory supports. Every week different foods were introduced to Benjamin with a rainbow theme. Initially the item would be placed on the table without drawing attention to it, then on his plate. After a steady progression — taking anywhere from a couple of weeks to several months — of touching the item, smelling it, and kissing it with his lips, Benjamin was then encouraged to try the food.“Let me tell you one of my most memorable mom moments,” said Marissa. “Six months after Benjamin had been at the school my formerly nonverbal son touched my head as I was helping him get dressed and said for the very first time, ‘I love you mama.’ My life was changed in an instant.”Now in his third year at Monarch Preschool, Benjamin speaks in four- to six-word sentences, comments on things he observes, addresses friends by name, and plays board games with his older sister. The team is considering plans for Benjamin’s transition and reintegration to his home school.33]]></page><page Index="36" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Financial Report34FOR THE YEAR ENDED JUNE 30, 2014Audited by McGladrey & Pullen, LLPExpenses by Typen Salary/Benefits n	Professional Fees n Occupancy	9% n Depreciation/Equipment	5% n Development	2%Expenses by ProgramnnnnnResidential/Group Services34%Education/Prevention 28%Community Services	22%General/Administrative/ 11%Fundraising Foster Care/Adoption5%66% 18%]]></page><page Index="37" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Donors* denotes deceased35We are deeply grateful to all of the individuals, corporations, and foundations who contributed to Bellefaire JCB this past fiscal year.The following contributions were made from July 1, 2013 through June 30, 2014. We make every effort to ensure our donor’s names and contributions are reported accurately and regret any inadvertent omissions.Bellefaire JCB is a Major Beneficiary of:Jewish Federation of Cleveland United Way of Greater Cleveland$100,000 +Elisabeth Severance Prentiss Foundation$50,000–$99,999Life Center for Autism Treu-Mart Foundation$25,000–$49,999Healthquest Foundation Roy A. Hunt Foundation Oswald Companies Sisters of Charity Foundation of Cleveland$10,000–$24,999The Alpha Group Isadore Binzer Irrevocable Trust Sam & Esther Friedman Foundation Russell & Leona Magid Arthur B. McBride Sr. Family Foundation MC Sign Company Jared & Stephanie MillerJohn P. Murphy Foundation Joshua & Natalie Rubin Nina and Norman Wain Family Foundation$5,000–$9,999Chelm Family Foundation David & Karen Crane First Giving Circle Fund Harry K. and Emma R. Fox Foundation Paul & Cookie JosephSteve & Debbie Joseph Faye Kaplan David & Jill Katz Toby D. LewisThe Milton and Tamar Maltz Family FoundationThe Edwin D. Northrup II Fund Royal Chemical Company Ltd. The Maurice Saltzman Youth Panel of theJewish Federation of Cleveland Bradley & Heather Schlang University Hospitals Ahuja Medical Center Wuliger Foundation Wuliger and Zegura Family$2,500–$4,999Anonymous Anthem Blue Cross Blue Shield Simon Badinter Baker Hostetler Steven & Carol EisenbergForest City Enterprises Irving & Frieda Hand JDN Fund John G. Johnson Construction Co. Marc* & Michele Krantz Dr. Samuel & Rosa Lobe Memorial Fund ofthe Jewish Federation of Cleveland MCPc, Inc. Abraham & Barbara Miller Philip NeshkinLarry & Julia Pollock Robert & Eileen Sill Todd & Stephanie Silverman Kenneth Tamar-Fink, Inc. Dominic Visconsi Timothy & Sandra Wuliger$1,000–$2,499Ann Abt America’s Best Transportation American Greetings Corporation Anonymous Avi Chai Michael Berman & Deborah W. Cowan Blue Technologies Big Brothers Big Sisters of America James Boyle, MD & Ivy Boyle, MD Robert & Beth Brandon Cohen & Company Daniel & Alisa Doctoroff Duke Realty Elivate Fitness]]></page><page Index="38" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Fifth Third Bank Irving & Gloria Fine Ruth Fisher vic & joan gelb George G. Golden Memorial Fund Eric Green Gross Builders Harley & Rochelle Gross Donald & Susan Groszek Eric & Andrea Hill Janitorial Services Inc. Junior League of Cleveland Melvin & Lola Kamins E.B. Katz Inc. Kohrman, Jackson & Krantz PLL Bradley & Tami Kowit David & Elizabeth Krantz Mr. & Mrs. David LaRue Mr. Richard Lichaw Littler Mendelson Mandel Foundation Marc’s McGladrey LLP Stanley & Barbara Meisel Northridge Health Center The Peterman and DeMinico FamilyFoundation Zachary & Taryn Ponsky Rehmann Financial Reserve Management Group Ronald McDonald House Charitiesof NE Ohio, Inc. Peter Rubin Saltzman Family Philanthropic Fund Brad & Sharon Sanders Schwebel Family FoundationSteven & Sonni Senkfor Scott & Shani Spiegle Stephen & Bonnie Spiegle Steven & Lauren Spilman Eva & Morris Stone Jewish Day NurseryFund of the Jewish Federation ofCleveland Ulmer & Berne LLP Mark & Melanie Wax The Harry and Jeanette WeinbergFoundation, Inc. Clara Weiss Fund Jim Whipkey Robert Wolff & Paula Silverman, MD Michael Zweig$500–$999AAMCO Transmission Shaw & Ally Abrams Alson Jewelers, Inc. Bentoff & Duber Co., L.P.A. Stephen & Susan Bergman Bluebridge Networks, LLC Tom & Colleen Browne Cynthia BurkettRobert Carlisle Chi Corporation Cleveland Clinic Children’s Hospital Stuart Cohen Coit Services Concrete Fastening Systems, Inc. Dale H. Cowan, MD & Susan Cowan Davis Automotive Group, Inc. Brian & Stacey Davis DeWitt’s Diamond & Gold Exchange Diamond Shine Car Wash SolutionKenneth E. Edelman, MD & Darcy Edelman Robert & Susan Englander Irwin & Barbara Feldman Fidelity Voice and DataFindley Davies Barry & Sam Gabel Ganley Bedford Imports, Inc. Steven & Marilyn Garfunkel Gene Ptacek & Son Fire Equipment Co., Inc. Dennis Glazer, MD & Marrianne Glazer Gary & Cathy Glazer Mildred Shelby Heller Memorial Fund Herman Textile Company, Inc. Andrew R. Hertz, MD & Linda C. Rae Keithley Instruments, Inc. Kottler Metal Products, Inc. James Kline Rik & Nancy Kohn James & Joe’l LaRose Jared S. Levin, MD & Lora Levin Al & Rosanne Levitt Stewart & Deborah Lewis Manhattan Strategy Group, LLC Mansour, Gavin, Gerlack & Manos Richard & Margaret Margolis Mars Electric Richard Marshall & Ms. Kathleen Newell McCarthy, Lebit, Crystal & Liffman Co.,L.P.A. Mirman Construction, Inc. Brian Murphy Park Synagogue Larry & Beth Pollack Regional Reps Corp. Charles B. & Carole Rosenblatt Steve Schecter & Elizabeth H. Dery36]]></page><page Index="39" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Shapero & Green, LLC Michael Sherwin Simpson Screen Print Edwin & Naomi Singer Sleggs, Danzinger & Gill, Co., LPA David SobleRichard & Heidi Solomon Southgate Lock & Security Spectrum Diversified Designs Inc. Roland & Judith StentaWilliam & Janet Stern Strategic College Funding Solutions Harris C. Taylor, MD & Diana Taylor John & Kathy Thompson Jack & Blanche Valancy Vendors Exchange International, Inc. Stephen & Penni Weinberg Welcome House West Shore Unitarian Universalist Church David S. White Ronald Zimmerman & Ann Bender$250–$499Bank of America Matching Gift Program Richard H. Bamberger Stuart M. & Lora Berkowitz David & Elaine BestRabbi Rick & Susan Block Henry R. Bloom, MD & Marilyn Malkin Burges & Burges Strategies, Inc. Marc S. & Viki Byrnes Michael & Kareen Caputo Michael & Lore Castrigano Gerald & Winnie Chattman Ruth & Louis Clay Endowment Fund of theJewish Federation of ClevelandDaniel & Paula Dreyfuss Douglas Dwosh Easton Telecom Services LLC Richard Fedorovich, CPA Brad FellowsRick & Lynn Fishman Michael and Julie Frayman FamilyFoundation Lauren Freiman Adam Fried Jeffrey Friedman, MD & Laura Friedman Scott & Paula Friedman David & Amy Garnitz Lyle Green Michael & Rosemary Ginzberg Stephen & Laurie Girsky Steve & Jane Goldstein Richard Horvitz and Erica Hartman-HorvitzFoundation Adam G. Jacobs, PhD & Melissa Jacobs Marti Katz Adam Kaufman Kumi Lane Lisa Bercu Levine Stephen Levine, MD & Lillian Levine Lippman Kanfer Family Foundation Lowy Haiman Fund Mark T. & Shari Meljac Merrill Lynch Chuck Nachman David & Muriel Nachman Ryan Novak Paul & Kim Pesses The Honorable Daniel A. Polster &Deborah Coleman The Reminger FoundationSol A. Ross Memorial Fund of the Jewish Federation of ClevelandSamuel B.Rubinstein Memorial Fund of the Jewish Federation of ClevelandBradley & Sharon Sanders Donald Scherzer Susanne Schroer Eva Weitzman Selcer Memorial Fund of theJewish Federation of Cleveland Shaker Auto Lease, Inc. Susan Silverberg Howard & Beth SimonJamie Spiegle Squire Sanders St. Francis of Assisi Student Council Elizabeth Stueber Roger M. Synenberg, Esq. &Joan Synenberg Dominic Visconsi Scott & Amy Whetzel Berle and Bruce P. Zeldman Memorial Fundof the Jewish Federation of Cleveland Robert ZimmermanGIFTS UP TO $249Brian Abraham Ethel Abrams Harvey & Judith Actor Kevin Adelstein Dorothy Adler Herbert & Rhoda Agin Tawana AllenLeea Allerding Renee Z. Althof Warren E. Anderson Paul Angart37]]></page><page Index="40" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Anonymous Susan Appelbaum Carey & Debbie Arnold Doug & Whitney Arnson Bill & Barbara Arsham Robyn Arsham Samantha Arth Pamela Ashby Barbara Ashdown Brad & Debra Auerbach Jennifer Ault Michael Ausperk Dan & Ziona Austrian Elana Averbach Patricia Averbach Rita Babin Lisa Bachman Alice R. Bailey Jason Baker & Cara Liles-Baker Susan Ballard Annette Lowe Barber Robin Barrisch John Barry Thomas & Leslie Basista Bill & Karen Bauza Irving Bayer Sandra Bean Barbara Becker Marilyn Bedol Stephanie Begley Joel & Amy Bender Lynn Berg Steven Berger Daniel Bergrin Marla BergrinDavid Berk Esther Berman Oscar Berman Stanley Bernath Leonard Bernstein, MD & Sue Bernstein Craig B. Berson Lauren Best Michael & Tina Best Beth Isreal - The West Temple Jacqui Biery Gary & Janice Bilchik BJ’s Wholesale Club Inc William Blair Phyllis Blake Chris Blankenship EJ Bloom Flora Blumenthal Jannie Blunt Ernest Bode, MD Jodi Bonda Madlyn Bookatz-Wagner Henry Borkovitz Tanya Borshov Patricia Boyd Angela Brainard Alissa Branford Herbert* & Helen Braun Michael & Rhonda Brennan Arthur & Karen Brown Harvey Brown Jack Brown Jo Anne Brown Melodi Brown Stanley & Barbara Brown George & Joanne BuchkoGary Buchler Armond & Amy Budish Eunice B. Buller Matt Buono Missy Burkett Cheryl Butler Derrick Butler Lois Butler Meredith Camp Denise Cannon Richard & Cheryl Carlisle Cindie Carroll-Pankhurst Joshua Caruso Aaron Cavano Andrew Ceifetz David Ceifetz David Cerone Frank Chahulski Cindy & Louis Chaiten Change For Charity Legacy Village Elaine Chaplin Rajdeep Chatterjee & Heta Shah Joshua Chefitz & Tyler Katz, MD Rabbi Mitchell & Wallis Chefitz Ian Cheistwer Mark Chekanow Mike & Sarah Chernoff Daniel Chessin Loren Chylla Wanda Clancy Cleveland Pride, Inc. Allen & Lori Cohen Jennifer Cohen Stacy Cohen Allison Cole38]]></page><page Index="41" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Barbara Colombi Paul & Erica Colton Chris Connor Darwin & Joanne Cooper Dana CornRobert & Carol Corn John Craig David Crampton & Meghan Hays Timothy Cronan Nancy Crum Jim Cullen & Chris Ruma-Cullen Louise Cullen Edward Cutler Seth Dabney & Deborah Chessin Peter Danford Price & Lisa David Gregory & Annette Davis Tom & Peggy Davis Denise Dawson Carly Day, MD Jean Day Harriet Deeds Steve Degyansky Timothy Del Papa Sue DeMay Christine DePamphilis David A. Derevjanik Jim Dery Anita Diamond Goldie Diamond Joyce Dickens-Loffree Elaine Dieckman Deb Donley Andrew Doris Michael DorisCraig Duber Larry Dubin Scott Dubin Michael Dukin Gladys Dunbar Karen Durland-Jones Glenn & Cindy Easton Jason Edelstein & Leah Wagner Elizabeth EisenbergErich Eisenloffel Thomas & Carla Eisdenloffel John & Elaine Hibshman Marc & Carrie Emch Patty Emser Gerald Erenberg, MD & Shulamith Erenberg Philip Erwin, MD Robert & Bonnie Evans Michael Feig Joseph & Shirley Felber Richard & Judy Felber Anne Feldman Edward S. Feldman, MD & CatherineFeldman Robert & Megan Fellinger Kathie Fellows Marilla Fellows Mark Fellows Tim Fellows Anna Fernando Felino & Cora Fernando Mark Philip Fernando Ellen Finestone Senator Eric D. & Amy Fingerhut Danielle Firem Hallie FisherDavid & Stacy Fisher Donald J. Fleishaker Nancy Flower Forest City Hebrew Benevolent Association Betty FormanPaul Forsyth Janice Foti James Fox Marcus Freeman Marc & Sharon Freimuth Amy FriedkinBarbara Friedman Howard & Patricia Friedman Steven A. & Lisa Friedman Jay S. & Hope Fromson Gerald Fuerst Laura Furman Anita Gabel Peter & Barbara Galvin Pamela Ganz David Garson Nancy Garson Lois A. Gaynor Tom Gelehrter Kenneth Gibb Audrey Glaser Warren & Deborah Goldenberg Sue Goldfarb Boston & Judith Goldman Donald & Sharon Goldman James & Jacqueline Goldman The Goldmiller Family Cheri Goldstein Carol Good Sidney R. Good39]]></page><page Index="42" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Heather Goodman Howard & Bonnie Goodman Margaret Goodman Harriet Gorden Eileen Gordon Joyce Gordon Lesley Gordon Bruce & Susie Goren Gil & Robin Graff Harry & Joyce Graham Barbara Grand Armin Green, MD & Sydell Green Brian & Robin Green Nancy Green Bluie Greenberg Erwin Greenblatt Mark Greenfield Robert & Sally Gries Gross & Gross LLC Judith Gross Jeffrey Grover Hal Gunder Gabe Gunder Josiah & Dana Haas Peter & Lee Haas Blaire & Dori Hass Kimberly Haber Gregory Hail Marjorie Hail Jeff & Laura Halpert Paul & Janet Havener Marjorie Heines Erica Henkin Carrie Henning Dan & Paula HermanJohn Hertzer, MD & Julie Hertzer, MD Mariam Prum Hess Elaine Hibshman Elizabeth J. HickleJan Hill Stanley Hirsch, DDS & Donna Hirsch Alan & Gayle Hochheiser Sharon G. Hohman Betty Holdstein Jon & Lesley Hoover Aaron & Carolyn Horowitz Robert & Sophie Horvath Lansing C. Hoskins, MD &Patience Cameron-Hoskins Michael G. & Susan Hyman Vincent Iannaggi Donald & Linda InsulEllen Irie Mark & Melissa Isakowitz Milana Iskhakova Howard & Lois Israel Maddy Jacobs Sanford Jacobs David Jaffe Michael Jaffe Jewish Communal Fund Jewish Family Service Association Andy Jones Joshen Paper & Packaging Rachel Kabb-Effron Ronald & Susan Kahn David Kaplan & Kathleene Smachlo Steve Karklin Jeffrey Karp Justin KattanLawrence & Karen Katz Lewis & Jan Katz Neil & Patti Katzman Aaron KaufmanHarvey & Carol Kaufman Todd Kay* Bradley Keare Jim Keeler & Vella Hammer Maura KeeneBob & Linda Kendall David Kessel & Rona Schwartz Pamela Kiltau Debbie Kinds Michael S. Klein Petra & Michael Klenz Stuart & Theresa Kline Roger Knipper & Irene Kravitz-Knipper Susan Koblitz Evan Kogan Joseph & Anita Kohler Laura Kosak Edward & Roslyn Kowit Jeffrey Krashin Donna Krasney Barbara Kraus Edward & Bonnie Kraus Georgian Kreps Leah Kuenzel Donna Kurit Jody Kutash David & Elana Landman Scott & Isabelle Lane Brian Lapidus Steve & Leslye Lapidus Ann Laurence40]]></page><page Index="43" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Derek & Nina Lawrence Melvin & Ina Lazerick Robert & Karla LeBlanc Jamie LebovitzLeff Electric Shirley Leikin Aimee Less Caroline Lesser Harold Levey Adam Levine Jim LevineJim Levine Marla Levine Rebecca Kopp Levine Harvey Lewis Judith Libava Scott Lichtenstein Benjamin Light Elizabeth Lindecke Charles W. & Alice F. Lissauer Larry & Barb Litvak Marc & Janet Litvak Peter & Helen Loewenstein Shelly Love Jeff Lox & Paul Nemitz Michael & Donna Ludwig Gladys Lukash Craig Lynch & Deborah Abrams Lawrence Mack Brian Magden Mandel Jewish Community Centerof Cleveland Bruce & Rita Mandel Judy Mann Chicky MargolisJeff & Nancy Markle Brian Marks Robert Marks Steven Marks Stephen Markus Peter & Claudia Marmaros Bill & Lori Mavrakis Thomas & Sara Mayer Doug & Ruth MayersPaul & Amelia McKenzie Brittany McLaughlin Kelly McLaughlin McPhillips Plumbing & HVAC Co. Thomas MechirSylvia Messing Hedy Milgrom Judith Miller Lisa Miller Margaret Miller Meghan Miller Michael Millstein, MD & Julie Millstein Andrew MirmanBruce Mirman Kristie Moffett Monica B’s Complete Hair Care Marc & Amelia Morgenstern Hadley Morgenstern-Clarren, MD &The Honorable Patti Morgenstern-Clarren Mel & Harriet Morris Jan & Linda Moskowitz Jeffrey MuenczStuart & Sally Neidus Elaine Neuman Kathleen Newton Nancy NicklesLawrence November Gregg Novicoff & Dawn Bear Lawrence Nudelman Mark Nulman Nurenberg Paris Debbie Obermiller Rob Oberst Richard & JoAnne O’Donnell Martin & Mary Kay O’Toole Mark & Esther Palevsky Rachel Palevsky Partners Environmental Consulting Mary Beth Pate Jeff Paull Jerald & Jane Payner Joe Pedro Shannon Pence Pam Perenti Sarah Perkins Patricia Perme Brett Piccus Phil & Edie Piccus Bob Platner Steve & Paula Platt Tod Podl, MD & Jody Podl Brad Pohlman Lisa Polak Adela Polster Elinor G. Polster Sheldon & Frances Polster Robert & Cynthia Port Robert Porter Joel Prager Daniel Price Jamie Price41]]></page><page Index="44" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Paul J. Priesand, DDS & Sharon Priesand Vicki Prokesh Stanley Prybe Jordanna QuinnDeborah Quintrell Rae-Ann Holdings, Inc. Kip & Sarah Reader Stanley Reid Benjamin Reinkober Barry & Susan Reis Dan Reisinger Erick M. Remer, MD & Erica Remer, MD Andy Resnick & Brett Katz Denys Resnick Jeff Resnick Marty Resnick & Sherri Appleton Todd Resnick David Reuven James Rich Rebecca Roberts Debora Rodriguez Kenneth & Amy Rogat Michael & Jodi Rogoff Ron Romaner & Jaynie Schultz Nancy Rome Dawn Rose Ray Rosen Charles & Maxine Rosenbaum Steve & Sari Rosenberg David M. Rosenberg, MD & Enid Rosenberg Sophia Rosenmoss Sharon Rosenzweig Illene Rosewater Matthew Rosner Jerry & Devorah Ross Alan & Barbara RosskammAlice Roth Bryan Roth, MD & Judith Roth David Roth Hope Roth Jerome M. & Mayda Rothenberg Paul Rotman Seth Rotz Sherry Rotz Richard & Diana Routman Sheryl Rowling Eric Rubin Richard T. & Penni Rubin Yitzchak & Allison Rubin Iris R. Rubinfield Rabbi Hal & Erika Rudin-Luria Sonya Ruff Marvin & Sharon Sable Barry & Florine Sadowsky Trina Saha Amy Sales Susan Saltzman Gary Salzinger Josh & Jill Samiss Donald & Paula Samuels Michael & Melinda Sapell Katherine S. Sawyer Judith Schaffer Herbert Schilling Elliott & Gail Schlang Evan & Dana Schlessinger Jerald & Marilyn Schneider Marcia Schneider David Schreibman Judy Seidel Justin Seidenberg Christin J. SeveraM & J Shafran Foundation Amnon Shai, PhD & Edia Shai William & Constance Sheehan Scott & Tanie Sherman Rita Sherwin Sanford M. & Estelle Shore Arik Shteinhauz Patricia Shular Jeff & Paige Shyken Terry & Sandra Silver Joseph & Susan Simms Skoda Minotti & Co. Joseph Skory Robert & Susan Sloan Jeni Smith Neil & Karila Smith Diane Snow Diane Snyder Vivian Solganik Doug Solomon Christopher & Sharon Soltes Jerry & Margery Somers Tom & Judy Spaulding Robert & Robin Spielman Sally Spitz Marly Edelsberg Stahl Clifford & Peggy Stark Michael Star David Steiger Leonard & Karen Steiger Paul & Edna Stein Lester & Elizabeth Stiel Linda Stoffl Becca Stolarsky Marc Stolarsky Melissa Stoloff42]]></page><page Index="45" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Catherine Stone Rabbi Susan B. Stone Barbara Strauss Chris & Elisa Strom Alexandra Sukhoy Stuart Sulzer Maureen Suster Target Brands, Inc. Marc & Ronna Taub Keith & Carey Teicher Stanley & Marianne Tepper Max Thomas William Thomas Mark J. & Mary Tichar Andrew & Sharon Tievsky Toledo Jewish Community Foundation Andrea Torf Howard Torf Karen Torf Mark, Meg & Mira Torf Martha Tripi Allan & Patricia Tuchman Dale C. Tucker Michael Tucker Henrietta Tumarkin Mindy Tumarkin Jule Turnoy Dennis & Amelia Vidmar Seth Vilensky Vocon, Inc. Chris & Cathy Von Ehrenkrook Susan Wachsstock Mark & Sally Wachter Scott & Beth Wachter Bradley & Jennifer WadsworthJon & Tanya Wagner Gloria Walas Timothy M. Walker Marcia Waxman Jeffrey & Ruth Weil The Adolf Weinberger Foundation Debra M. WeinertDon & Jill Weinstein Edward & Gail Weinbtraub Janis Weintraub Eleanor Weisman Herbert Weiss Jerome F. Weiss & Judith Salomon Robert D. & Carol Weitzner Steve & Chris Weitzner Morris & Jeannette Weledniger Margaret Wells Nancy Welsh Robert & Brenda Weltman Steven & Trudy Wiesenberger Mark Wiley James & Eileen Wilkoff David Willen, DDS & Carol Willen Leon & Ellen Williams Michael Wilson Matt Winograd Terance Wintering Jessica Wise Harvey A. & Judy Wiseberg Joan Wittenberg Marlene Wolf William A. Wortzman Jason & Allison Wuliger Matt & Joanna Wyner Darrell & Andria YoungHayden Young Neil & Wendy Young Steven Young Daniel Yulish Sandy Zabell Michael Zacharia Jane Zagorski Richard & Marcie Zeiger Adam Zelwin Alice Zimbler Maxene Zion Lori Zocolo Kalman Zucker & Mary Frances Haerr, MDGIFTS IN KINDThe AdCom Group African Safari Wildlife Park American Greetings Corporation Amy Joy Donuts Andrews Osborne Academy Association of Legal Administrators AT&T Audrey’s Sweet Threads Beanie Baby puppies Beck Theater Ben & Jerry’s Joanne Berkovitz Bialy’s Bagels Dan Barnett Bill Barber Bimbo Bakeries Eric & Judy Bell Blue Technologies Robert & Beth Brandon Jordan Brown43]]></page><page Index="46" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Cleveland Cavaliers Jim & Ann Clark Cleveland Clinic Cleveland Coca-Cola Bottling Co. Cleveland Heights-University HeightsLibrary Cleveland Indians Cleveland Museum of Natural History Cleveland Zoological Society Coldstone Creamery Corky & Lenny’s D & R Bagels Dave’s Markets Discount Drug Mart Discovery Photo Doner Advertising Duke Realty Jeff Ehrbar & Diane Singer Elite Stables Fairport Asset Management Fandango Brad Fellows First Watch Bill & Susan Flinn Gary Flinn & Susan Munteen Holly Flinn Nick Flinn Richard Flinn Victoria Flinn Flower Entertainment Inc. Freeway Lanes of Solon Mark Freiman Entertainment Valerie Furst Genie Repros Giant Eagle - SolonGross Schechter Day School Half Price Books Hands on Pottery HeinensHomewood Suites by Hilton Mary Hussing Leslie Immel J. PIstoneJack’s Delicatessens, Inc. Steve & Deborah Joseph David & Jill Katz Adam KaufmanJoJo D. Klown Eileen S. Kollins Lois Krebs Ladies & Gentlemen Spa - Aveda Lake Erie Monsters Game Tickets Sidney & Fran LaskyGretchen Levy Jim Lockshaw Maltz Museum of Jewish Heritage Mandel Jewish Community Center Fawnda Martin Lisa Martin Tim & Heidi McCabe Jaime McCain Menchie’s Mercer Elementary School Miles Market Mitchell’s Ice Cream Mitty Fowler & Family Jenny Monte William & Eudice Morse Robert & Julie Namy National Council of Jewish WomenJoyce Oliver Orange High School Julie Patton Pepsi Beverage Company Pizzazz On the Circle Larry & Julia Pollock Rascal House Pizza Scott Robertson Rosalina MarkFrank Salon Joshua & Natalie Rubin Sherwin-Williams Ted & Natalie Silverberg Todd & Stephanie Silverman Sisu Salon Jeni Smith Kim Stearns, MD Patricia Stevenson Stone Oven Alexandra Sukhoy Temple Emanu El Edward Thomas Trader Joe’s U.S. Foods Roberta Wasserstrom Western Reserve RestaurantManagement, Inc. Wheel of Fortune Elizabeth Wolanski Timothy & Sandy Wuliger Audra Zarlenga44]]></page><page Index="47" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Bellefaire JCB Board of DirectorsBellefaire JCB Affiliations and AccreditationsApplewood Centers Child Welfare League of AmericaCoalition for Cuyahoga County’s Children & YouthHague Accreditation through the Council on AccreditationJewish Federation of Cleveland The Joint CommissionNational Association for Children’s Behavioral HealthOhio Council of Behavioral Health & Family Service ProvidersOhio Departments of:• Developmental Disabilities• Education• Job and Family Services• Mental Health and Addiction ServicesOhio Step Up to Quality United Way of Greater Cleveland Wingspan Care GroupAs of 6/30/13EXECUTIVE COMMITTEEBradley J. Schlang,Chair, Board of DirectorsAdam G. JacobsPresidentBrian DavisSecretaryStephanie SilvermanAssistant SecretaryStephen L. BergmanTreasurerBeth Brandon Marc Krantz z"l Stephanie Miller Josh Rubin Bradley N. Sanders Rob WolffSandra WuligerDIRECTORS AT LARGEAlly Abrams Susan Block Jeri Chaikin Loren Chylla Beth Dery Steve Eisenberg Robert Englander Lev GonickJulie Hertzer Deborah Joseph David Katz Adam Kaufman Jennifer Korach Ed KrausJim Levine Scott Lichtenstein Mark Munsell Daniel Polster Steve Saltzman Sonni Senkfor Susan Silverberg Diane Singer Kathy Thompson Steve WeitznerDIRECTORS EMERITILois Gaynor Donald Goldman David Nachman Nancy Rome Charles Rosenbaum Jan Stern Steven Wiesenberger Sandra WuligerDIRECTORS FOR LIFEGerald Chattman Irwin Feldman vic gelb Larry Pollock Edwin Roth Peter Rubin Vivian SolganikORGANIZATIONAL DIRECTORSSusan Saltzman Marvin Smith Rick Solomon Evan Witt]]></page><page Index="48" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Susan Kandzer DesignBellefaire JCBfOonrexPcoellolecnkcCei.r.c.lefor wellness... for children 22001 Fairmount Blvd Cleveland, OH 44118 (216) 932-2800www.bellefairejcb.org]]></page></pages></Search>